Lantz Warrick

Web | iOS Developer

M (360) 674-9928

<u>betalantz@gmail.com</u>

linkedin.com/in/betalantz

Greater Seattle Area betalantz.com github.com/betalantz

LANGUAGES

JavaScript (ES6) Python Swift HTML5 CSS3

FRONT END

Angular 4 Bootstrap jQuery Ajax

BACK END

Express Node.js NPM/Yarn/ Bower Django Flask Socket.IO AWS EC2 Nginx MAMP

DATABASES

SQL NoSQL Mongoose CoreData

MongoDB MySQL

SQLite SOFTWARE

Visual Studio Code Git Xcode Mac/ Windows MySQL Workbench

MISC

OOP RESTful API Agile/Scrum Kanban

Summary

I am a Web and Mobile Developer knowledgeable in Python, Javascript and Swift, with a passion for innovative technology. My liberal arts education, combined with nearly a decade as a language educator and entrepreneur, has taught me how to ask the right questions to identify core problems, and given me the intellectual tools to solve them. I am seeking an opportunity to collaborate with a team building creative web products which positively impact lives and communities.

Experience

Software Development Trainee | Coding Dojo, Bellevue, WA July-November 2017

- Completed 1000+ learning and development hours across 40+ web and mobile projects using Python, MEAN, and Swift/iOS stacks.
- Achieved proficiency in each full-stack in under 4-weeks.

Head Teacher/Co-owner | IvyTree Language Center, Taipei, Taiwan 2012- July 2017

- Positively impacted student outcomes through employment of educational technology in the classroom, including interactive whiteboards (IWB), tablets, and networked student input devices.
- Increased student enrollment by 35% and grew staff by 66%.
- Created and taught curricula for all classes, Grades 2 through 9

ESL Teacher | Alliance English, Taipei, Taiwan

ESL Teacher | Happy Marian Children's World, Taipei, Taiwan

July 2011- June 2013

July 2009- June 2011

ESL Teacher | Hess Education Organization, Taipei, Taiwan

July 2008- June 2009

Education

Coding Dojo, Bellevue, WA | Full-stack Web Development Reed College, Portland, OR | B.A., Classics

Projects

Survey Circus (MEAN)

A fun survey app with user registration, validations, persistent data and CRUD operations, using Bootstrap, built in under 4.5 hours and deployed to AWS, earning 9.55/10 points on final stack exam. (18.220.86.253)

Zap Bam Pow (iOS)

A multi-player, networked 'laser-tag' game for iOS 11 built in 4 days as part of a 3-person team using Swift's new ARKit and socket.io on a Node.js server. The project won a competition across four Coding Dojo campuses. (https://youtu.be/Yhwohl7K5AU)